PAVEL TARASHKEVICH

 $+48516106193 \diamond Warsaw$, Poland

pavel.tarashkevich@gmail.com \leftrightarrow linkedin.com/in/pashok3d

SUMMARY

NLP Engineer with 3+ years of professional experience in Machine Learning, Deep Learning and development of commercial NLP applications. I have experience in building end-to-end AI solutions, starting from prototyping and implementation to training, optimization and production deployment.

SKILLS

Technical Skills Python (NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn), Deep Learning (PyTorch, Lightning),

NLP (HuggingFace, Transformers), SQL, Git, AWS, Docker, CI/CD

Languages Polish, English

EXPERIENCE

NLP Engineer

Edrone

Sep 2022 - Present

Warsaw. Poland

- Implemented and deployed a custom spell checker to correct misspellings in user queries. When no other off-the-shelf solutions were accepted, my implementation proved to be fast and accurate, reducing the "zero results" rate from 20% to 13%.
- Researched and implemented a custom BERT-like model to detect and identify entities in user queries. Integrated these models into the existing workflow, resulting in a performance boost of the rule-based approach from 89% to 93% (F1).

NLP & Machine Learning Engineer

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022 Warsaw, Poland

Orange Polska

- Applied transfer learning techniques to adapt Large Language Models for the telecom domain, resulting in a substantial performance boost (from 0.84 to 0.92 F1) for understanding and classifying user intents.
- Created models for sentiment and satisfaction prediction that helped to identify AI assistant weaknesses, which was crucial for reducing customer churn by 5 percentage points.
- Combined recurrent networks and language models to predict user behaviour, resulting in a notable 15% increase in contact resolution rate.

Machine Learning Intern

Orange Polska

Jul 2020 - Sep 2020 Warsaw, Poland

• Designed new data-labeling workflow based on active learning technique that helped to significantly speed up the process of manual dataset preparation.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science, Warsaw University of Technology

Expected 2023

Thesis: Transformers for OCR and ASR spellcheck

Bachelor of Computer Science, Warsaw University of Technology

Thesis: Adaptive sentiment analysis in polish with BERT

2017 - 2021